Guide to the New York Committee for Occupational Safety and Health (NYCOSH) Records WAG.029
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series III: Unprocessed Material, 1971-2011; 545012
  - Box 9, 1980-1987; cuid7957; 545018
    Occupational Health and Safety Reports and Pamphlets, Labor Education Center Correspondence, Memoranda and Assembly Bills, Bay Area COSH Fact Sheets, COSH Mailing Lists, Minority Workers: Reports, Newsletters, and Files, Childcare, Ceramics, Chemical Storage & Disposal Information, Journals & Reviews on Safety and Environment, Labor Safety and Health Institute Newsletters, Booklet: OSHA Standards, Construction and Safety Policy, U.S. Department of Health and Education Mailings, Brochures: Right to Know, U.S. Department of Labor News, Safety Newsletters, Educational Course Outline on Toxic Waste Disposal, Carpenters' Union Correspondence, Safety and Health Manuals, Report on New York State Safety and Health Concerns, Correspondence and Financial Records, Handouts
  - Box 10, 1986-1989; cuid7958; 545019
    NYCOSH: Fliers and Mailings on Criminal Prosecution for Occupational Injury, Death and Disease, Medical Bills, CT Interlocal Risk Management Agency, Local Correspondence and Mailings, Handwritten Notes and Suggestions, Reports, Bridge Market, Right to Know Letter, Correspondence and Newsletters: Jim Conti Material, Karen Cohen Files, Notes, Correspondence, and Reports, Angela DeVito files, Cate Poe Files, NY Staff Meeting Reports, Handwritten Notes on Transit Workers, TBTABA Mortality Study, SEIU Correspondence and Reports, Ruth Emler Recruitment, Westchester Meetings, NYCOSH Asbestos Meetings, Financial Records, Jackie Nowell's Files
  - Box 11, 1987-1992; cuid7959; 545020
    Incoming and Outgoing Correspondence: Jul 1 - Dec 31 1987, Local Files for Great Neck Teachers, Agenda and Handwritten Notes, Teacher Forms, Filers, and Information, Massanequa Federation of Teachers, AFT: Mattituck-Cutchogue T.A., Millbrook Training Files, Nassau Community College Staff Association and Locals, NYSUT Asbestos Abatement Reports, New Rochelle Training Materials, Correspondence, Pamphlets, Investigation Summaries, North Rockland Files, NYU, Oceanside School, Professional Staff Congress Training Materials, Rockville Center Teachers Association
  - Box 12, 1987-1994; cuid7960; 545021
    NYCOSH Board Agenda Correspondence, Membership Renewal Report, Accounts and Balance Sheets, Board Meeting Minutes, Workers' Compensation Committee, Proposed By-Law Amendment, Staff Meeting Agenda and Notes, Fashion Institute Training Manual, Files from Long Island Office, Mount Sinai Advisory Boards, Fliers, NYCOSH Resource Center, TB Reports, PERB Case concerning Tuberculosis Testing, NYS Department of Health Studies, TB in NYC Files, Correspondence, Reports, News, State Guidelines, Notes and Newsletters, NIOSH Recommended Guidelines, NIOSH-CDC-OSHA-GNYHA, OSHA Forms, Hep. C Files, Testing: Guidelines, Policy, Articles, Testimony and Hearings, Prevention and Reduction of Needlestick Injuries, National Leaders Conference on HIV/HBV, Federal Statistics
  - Box 13, 1974-1994; cuid7961; 545022
    NYCOSH Newsletters (and Correspondence regarding Newsletters): WOSH News, Work & Health, WashCOSH, WisCOSH, Hazards Communication, Bits of News (Mailings and Newspapers), B.C. Workers' Health Newsletter, TNCOSH Health & Safety, UticaCOSH, SACOSH, SCCOSH, RiCOSH, Rocky Mountain Project, SEACOSH, etc.
  - Box 14, 1974-1991; cuid7962; 545023
    Correspondence and Report to the Joint OER/PEF Health and Safety Committee, Draft Safety Petitions, Rules and Regulations, NYS/PEF Health and Safety Training Program (Monthly Report), Hunter College Materials, New York State Employee's Health and Safety Report, Booklets and Information on National OSH, VDT Legislation and NYS Campaign Material, Exclusive Sheet Brochure & Articles, Resources, Translations and Forms, NYCOSH Reports, VDT Newsletters and Presentations, Meetings Overview and Minutes, Health and Safety Training Guidelines, Training Correspondence, OCAW Health and Safety News, Lab Safety and Hazard Recognition Brochures, Pamphlets, and Newsletters, International Chemical Workers Union, Institute for Labor Studies Files, Fact Sheets + Requests, HMO Packets, Memoranda, Fax, and Handwritten Notes
  - Box 15, 1987-1992; cuid7963; 545024
    NYCOSH Union Membership Forms, Benefits and Claims, International Board of Teamsters, Locals Correspondence, Payroll and Balance Sheets, Newspapers, TWU Information and Memoranda, Asbestos and Room Air Quality Tests, Air Transport Files, Handwritten Notes, Balances, News, United Food and Commercial Workers, Joint Board Union Newsletters, Health Conference Fliers, WGA Files, Con Edison Sites Visits and Reports, Schematics, Handwritten Notes, Outlines, Power Plant Reports, UFT Grant Surveys, United Federation of Teachers Contract, Newsletter on OSHA Guidelines, Central Islip Teachers Association Files
  - Box 16, 1971-1993; cuid7964; 545025
    NYCOSH Potential Health Hazard Notices and Materials, Occupational Safety and Health Brochures, Health and Safety News, BHOPAL Files, Hazard Elimination Through Local Participation Act, Right to Know Files, Draft Summaries, OSHA Personnel Guides and Record Keeping, OSHA Articles, OSHA under Reagan: Notices, Files, News, Hazard Reports, Balance Sheets and Reports, Talking Points on Worker Safety and Health, Newspaper Supplements, Safety and Health Brochures, New Jersey Environmental Federation, NCCOSH, NHCOSH, Medical Monitoring News, NYS Board of Standards and Appeals, OSHA Newsletters, COSH Addresses, Injured Workers of New York Correspondence and Reports, American Labor Newsletter, Solidarity Magazine, Newspaper Clippings, State-by-State COSH Organizations, JOSHRC Newsletter
  - Box 17, 1980-1995; cuid7965; 545026
    CWA Negotiations: General Co. of California, Correspondence to and from NYCOSH, Newspaper Articles, Occupational Health Newsletter, Waste and Superfund Programs, State Bulletins and Newsletters on Occupational Health, Alice Hamilton Quarterly, State COSH Fliers, News, and Leaflets, Correspondence from COSH AFL-CIO Affiliates
  - Box 18, 1980-1989; cuid7966; 545027
    Various State VDT Legislation and Guidelines, Executive Orders, International (Trade Union) Guidelines, VDT Coalition Meetings, Agendas, Minutes, NYC VDT Bill: May 19 Testimony, Asbestos Handling Course Material, EPA Reports, Paper Workers Material, GMB Safety Reps Handbook, Safety Reps Guide and Handbook, Organizing and Union Materials and Regulations, CWA -- Occupational Safety and Health Fact Sheets, Conference Materials, Brochures, Handwritten Notes, Asbestos Control Program: Rules and Regulation
  - Box 19, 1982-1988; cuid7967; 545028
    NYCOSH Incoming and Outgoing Correspondence: Jul 1984-1986, Staff Issues, Mailings, Memoranda, Reports, Forms, Environmental Cancer Information, Contributions and Congressional Awards, Steering Committee (Mailing List & Sheet with Addresses & Phone Numbers), Financial Records
  - Box 20, 1982-1992; cuid7968; 545029
    NYCOSH Mailings and Correspondence, Members/Unions/Board, Working Well: NYS/PEF Health & Safety Training Program, Labor/Management Health and Safety Survey, Review of Health and Safety Concerns, Alaska Health Project Booklet, Slides, National Education Association: Health and Safety Handbook, Helpline Directory, North American Free Trade Act, OSHA Reform, Safety and Health Spotlight, Newspaper Clippings, Directory of US House of Representatives, Congressional Correspondence, Election Material, Notes, Fliers, and Proposed Agendas, Senate Committee on Labor Reports, Newsletters and Brochures on OSHA Reform, WISCOSH Study, OSH Stats, Legislative Bills, OSHA Review Commission, Magazine Clippings, Rules and Regulations on Access to Records, Final Report on State Mandated and Other Worker Protection Programs, Right to Know and Occupational Safety and Health Newsletters
  - Box 21, 1985-1996; cuid7969; 545030
    Resource Manual: Chemical Emergency Response/Hazardous Waste, Health and Safety Bulletins, Handwritten Notes, Correspondence, Taskforce Member List, VDT User Bill of Rights, Fliers and Leaflets, Legal Memoranda, Workers' Compensation Committee Minutes, Repetitive Strain Injury Task Force, Newspaper Clippings, Workers' Memorial Day Guide, Workers' Comp Legislation and Notes, Correspondence, Poughkeepsie BBD, Administrative Inventory of Workers Comp in Various States, RSI Articles, Occupational Health Clinics, Office Hazards, Health and Safety Newsletters, VDT Information, Health Issues, and Legislation, Labor Studies: Advanced Seminar in Occupational Health and Safety, Office Hazards and Control Report, Nurses' Committee Memorandum, and City Health Information
  - Box 22, 1987-1997; cuid7970; 545031
    NYS Department of Labor Hazard Abatement Board: Occupational Safety and Health Training and Education Proposal, Resolutions, Sign-Up Sheets, Publicity Material, Correspondence, 2005 COSH Conference Agenda, Worker Safety News, WisCOSH Newsletters, the Politics of Workers' Compensation, New York City Right to Know Programs, Memoranda, Articles, and News: Community Right to Know Information, Discussion Topics for the Public (Drafts), Hazard Communication: Right to Know Pamphlets, Brochures, Proposals and Statement, Newspaper Clippings, Board of Inquiry Reports: Rules and Regulations, NYCOSH Memoranda, Education Centers, Organizational Charts, Pamphlets, Board Meeting Material and Notes, Asbestos Booklet, Indoor Air Research, Department of Health Files, Department of Labor PESH Program, NYS Occupational Safety and Health Training Program, Institute for Environmental Education and Justice, Clinton/Gore - OSH, Subcommittee on Violence in the Workplace, Wrongful Death Files, Workers' Compensation Roundtables, VDT Coalition Files and Veto, News Articles, DC 37 Contract, OSH Stats, Non-profit News, Occupational Health Clinics and Evaluation
  - Box 23, 1984-1992; cuid7971; 545032
    NYCOSH Outreach & Sales Printed Materials, Newspaper Articles and Press Releases, Department of Labor Proposals, Correspondence from Department of Intergovernmental Affairs, New York Committee for Occupational Safety and Health Budget, Hazard Recognition and Control Study, NYSUT Contract, Department of Labor Forms, Conference and Meeting Materials, Financial Records and Balance Sheets, NY Committee for Occupational Safety and Health, Teacher Grant Proposal, AFL-CIO News, Transformer Files, Occupational Safety Training/Education Contracts, Summary of Work Program and Budget, Asbestos Reports and OSHA Files, Electronic Workers of America Files, Wilson-Shriver Grievances, Spanish Fact Sheet, Local Files: Firefighters, Graphics
  - Box 24, cuid7972; 545033
    Correspondence Outgoing and Incoming, Meeting Files, Civil Court Information, EWVIDCO, Memoranda and Agendas, Network Meeting Reports, Nomination Letters, Department of Community and Preventative Medicine, Operating Budget Figures, Technical Proposals, Hospital Records, NYCOSH Elections, Committee Memoranda, Susan O'Brien Files, Press Statements re: Managed Care, VDT Information and Bibliographies, Reports on VDTs, Technical Reports, National Research Council, Eye Strain Programs, Ergonomic Office Reports and Guidelines, VDT Articles, Job Stress, Lighting, and Hazards
  - Box 25, 1984-1996; cuid7973; 545034
    Audio Reels: Asner WMD PSA, Ed Asner Occupational Safety & Health, Audio Cassettes: A. Francisca Ruiz, Flor Reynoso, Matilde Castro, Trina Semorile, US Department of Labor Correspondence, Budget Statistics, NYCOSH Correspondence, FOIA Information, Newspaper Clippings, Work Injuries by Industry Tables, Department of Health Correspondence, Health and Safety Newsletters, Contact Information, OSHA Reform, National COSH 2000 Files, Local COSH Files
  - Box 26, 1983-2003; cuid7974; 545035
    AFL-CIO Health and Safety Committee Meeting Agenda, Report of Resolution Compliance, Health Packet and Policy, Shipyard Policy and Hazards, Compensation Forms for Injuries, Newspaper Clippings, Articles for Publication, NYS Labor Department Audit, NYS Labor Religion Coalition, Fliers and Notices, Advert Draft, Union Renewal Letters, Local Correspondence, Center for Occupational Hazard Reports, Pregnancy Rights, Articles and Inspection Schedules, Information in Spanish, Ed Wallace PCB Bill, OSHA Accident and Injury Stats, FOIA, Fact Sheets, Legislative Memos, Ventilation Reports, Subway Reports, WTC, Workplace Violence, NYCOSH Retreats, Safety and Health in the 90s, Infectious Disease in the Workplace, Fighting TB in the Workplace, WPV Regulations and Guidelines, Frank Goldsmith Files, Save OSHA Campaign
  - Box 27, 1990-2005; cuid7975; 545036
    Legal Contracts, Riders, and Facsimile, American Journal of Public Health, Newspaper and Magazine Articles, Asbestos Booklet and Workers Compensation Claim, NYCOSH Correspondence, AFL-CIO News and Correspondence, Statewide COSH Newsletters, Occupational Safety and Health Seminar, Legal Correspondence, Workplace Safety Outlines, Indoor Air Pollution Files, Health and Safety Organizing Committee Drive and Fact Sheet, The First National People of Color Environmental Leadership Summit, Mount Sinai Queens Project, State and Federal IMB Workers' Compensation, Clinic Funding, WMD Organizing Packets, Safety and Health Packets, Workers' Memorial Day, Administrative Memoranda, UFCW 174, Dave Newman's Basic Safety Health and Training Materials
  - Box 28, 1979-1984; cuid7976; 545037
    Office Automation (General): Information Forms, Correspondence, VDT Booklet, Mailings Correspondence, Order Complaints, NIOSH Materials: Study, Reports, Finding Standards, Photographs, Union Times Newsletters, Articles, and Newspaper Clippings, NYCOSH Newsletters, Publicity and Press Release Materials, Product Surveys, CRT & AFSCME Files, Notes and Questionnaires from VDT Conference, Bell System Guide, OSH Bibliographies, VDT and Radiation Materials and Studies, Committee Reports, Wang CRT Workstation Files, British Society for Social Responsibility in Science Correspondence, Pregnancy and Stress Studies, VDT Committee NIOSH Proposal
  - Box 29, 1986-1989; cuid7977; 545038
    Research Files: Stress in the Workplace, Union Membership Forms: Local 400, Amalgamated Clothing & Textile Workers Union, Methodist Hospital, New York Hospital and Care Employees, National Union of Hospital and Health Care Employees, Millinery Workers Union, OSHA Citations, American Federation of Government Employees, Air Transport Workers, Association of Municipal Employees, Bakery, Confectionary, and Tobacco Workers Union, Civil Service Employee Association, Communication Workers of America, NYCOSH Healthcare Fliers, United Auto Workers, Home Care Employees, Real Estate Employees, NYC / Sewage, Department of Traffic Employees, Brooklyn Library Guild, AFSCME District Council 37, Bridge and Tunnel Maintainers, College Assistants, Health & Hospitals, Departments of Parks, Doctors Council, Electrical Employers, Utility Workers, Uniformed Fire Fighters Association
  - Box 30, 1984-2000; cuid7978; 545039
    NYCOSH Asbestos Petitions, Intake Forms, Subway Campaign, Correspondence, News Articles, VDT Coalition, Poster Campaign, Agenda, Booklets, Fliers, Newsletters, and Newspaper Clippings, Individual Files, NYCOSH Board Agenda, Westchester Office Lease, Staff Relations and NYCOSH Committee Meeting Minutes
  - Box 31, 1988-1991; cuid7979; 545040
    Correspondence Incoming and Outgoing, Pamphlets, Rescue Center Files, Support Letters, Budget and Fiance, EPA Materials
  - Box 32, 1982-1990; cuid7980; 545041
    Correspondence, Notes, Union Forms: Motion Picture Studio Mechanics, Projectionists, International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Radio & TV Broadcast Engineers, Teamsters, Garment Workers, Iron Workers, Air Transport Workers, American Federation of Musicians, Hyde Park Plumbers, Painters, Paperworkers, American Postal Workers Union, Police, Landlords, Store Owners, Screen Actors Guild, Research and Fliers: Safety and Health on the Job, LIRR Training Manual, Memoranda, Asbestos Training: Exams and Evaluation, Protective Equipment and Emergency Procedures, OSH Government Contacts and Offices, Background Information on Locals, Legal Aid Society Files and Correspondence, Labor International Union of North America, Broadcasting NABET Files, PEF State Insurance Fund, SEIU, Social and Health Workers Files, Interims
  - Box 33, 1987-1990; cuid7981; 545042
    Memoranda, Correspondence, Notes, Reports, Newsletters: AHOHC Asbestos Manual: Comments on Drafts, Respirators, WISH/UFT Training, Wisconsin Files, Small-Scale Duration, Training Manual and Asbestos Abatement and Guides, Teachers Union Files, Evaluation Forms, EPA Materials and Training Grant, NYC Certification, Screening and Education Task Force, ACORN Training, New York and New Jersey School Inspections, AHERA Fact Sheets and Compliance
  - Box 34, 1978-1987; cuid7982; 545043
    NYCOSH Publications for FIAT Files, Newspapers and Newsletters, Correspondence, Membership Alerts, Handwritten Notes, OCOSH Files, Personnel Records, Committee Files, Political Education Reports, Petitions re: Occupational Safety, Surveys, Photographs, Newspaper Clippings, Workers' Bill of Rights, Fundraising Benefits Photographs and Leaflets, Mailing Lists and Individual Records, VDT Answer Sources, Safety and Health Memos and Briefs, Serials and Booklets, Job Safety Newsletters, Advertising: Offices 80's, VDT Checklist, Legislative Committees, and Foreign Pamphlets, Union Renewal Letters, Science for Citizens Planning Summary
  - Box 35, 1978-1986; cuid7983; 545044
    Asbestos Committee Files, Mailing Lists and Personnel Files, Correspondence, Financial Records, Request for Assistance Forms, Price Listings, Union Forms, Organizing Committees, Articles on Union Papers, Management and Business Articles about VDTs, Automated Times: Massachusetts, CWA Packet, United Nations & VDTs, Mount Sinai Newspaper Guild Study, VDT Compensation of Workers, VDT Bookorders, Financial Records, Pamphlets on Occupational Safety, NYCOSH Publication List Correspondence, Metropolitan Outreach Letter, "Health Protection" VDT Article, The Newspaper Guild: VDT - Health Collective Bargaining Kit, NHS Education, NYS Department of Education and Welfare, Urban Environment Correspondence, Reproductive Effects, Mailings, Union Forms, NYCOSH: New Directions Proposal
  - Box 36, 1982-1990; cuid7984; 545045
    Leaflets, Correspondence, News, Handwritten Notes, and Reports: White Lung Association, Asbestos Standards, Rulemaking, State Files for Various Asbestos Programs, State Law, Environmental Encapsulating, Asbestos Task Force, ACD Asbestos Reports, EPA Dialogue Process, EPA Draft O&M Program, Revised Drafts, Hearings and Appeals, Press Clippings: Asbestos in Schools
  - Box 37, 1983-1984; cuid7985; 545046
    Newsletters: Job Hazards Fact Sheet, NYCOSH Testimonial Dinner, Construction Health Hazards and Prevention, 1983 Long Island Conference, NYCOSH Picnic Materials, Mailings, Safety Reports, Asbestos Conference Packets, Newsletters, Reports, and Literature, Program Notes, Press Releases re: OSHA closings, Public Citizen Litigation (Hazard Communication), Intro to Health Hazards in Theater Crafts, Health Safety in Schools, Product Research, Asbestos Conference Endorsements, Cocktail Fundraisers, VDT Conference, VDT 9 to 5 Campaigns, Copies of "In These Times"
  - Incoming and Outgoing Correspondence, HIV Training Materials, 1992-1993; cuid7986; 545047 (Box 38)
  - Subject Files on Occupational Hazards: PCBs, Pesticides, Reproductive Hazards, and Indoor Air Quality, circa 1980s-2000s; cuid7987; 545048 (Box 39)
  - Subject Files on Occupational Hazards: Asbestos, Sexual Harassment, and Shiftwork, circa 1980s-2000s; cuid7988; 545049 (Box 40)
  - Subject Files on Occupational Hazards: Asbestos, circa 1980s-2000s; cuid7989; 545050 (Box 41)
  - Subject Files on Occupational Hazards: World Trade Center, Women's Health, and Young Workers, circa 1980s-2000s; cuid7990; 545051 (Box 42)
  - Subject Files on Occupational Hazards: Asbestos, circa 1980s-2000s; cuid7991; 545052 (Box 43)
  - Subject Files on Occupational Hazards: Lead and General Environmental, circa 1980s-2000s; cuid7992; 545053 (Box 44)
  - Subject Files on Occupational Hazards: Indoor Air Quality and Firefighters, circa 1980s-2000s; cuid7993; 545054 (Box 45)
  - Subject Files on Occupational Hazards: S (mostly Solvents), circa 1980s-2000s; cuid7994; 545055 (Box 46)
  - Subject Files on Occupational Hazards: General Environment, Occupational Injuries, and Dyes, circa 1980s-2000s; cuid7995; 545056 (Box 47)
  - Subject Files on Occupational Hazards: Dyes, Bhopal, AIDS/HIV, and Hazardous Waste, circa 1980s-2000s; cuid7996; 545057 (Box 48)
  - Subject Files on Occupational Hazards: Reproductive Hazards and Domestic Violence, circa 1980s-2000s; cuid7997; 545058 (Box 49)
  - Subject Files on Occupational Hazards: Young Workers and Training Materials, circa 1980s-2000s; cuid7998; 545059 (Box 50)
  - World Trade Center, Immigrant Rights, Legislative Files, and Executive Board Minutes (2002), circa 2000s; cuid7999; 545060 (Box 51)
  - Testimony and Correspondence File (1994-1998), 1980-1998; cuid8000; 545061 (Box 52)
  - Box 53, 1994-2000s; cuid8001; 545062
    Correspondence File (1994), Executive Board (includes minutes from 2000-2001), and Legislative Files
  - Box 54, 1994-2000; cuid8002; 545016
    Correspondence Files
  - Box 55, 1980s-early 1990s; cuid8003; 545015
    Legal Files, Testimony, and Legislative Files
  - Box 56, 1980s-early 2000s; cuid8004; 545014
    Newsletters and Press Material
  - Box 57, circa 1990-2009; cuid8005; 542886
    New York State AFL-CIO Lobbying Materials, NYCOSH Workers Compensation Committee, and Correspondence
  - Box 58, circa 1990-2009; cuid8006; 542885
    Correspondence
  - Box 59, circa 1982-2009; cuid8007; 542884
    Conference Materials (Especially Workers Memorial Day)
  - Box 60, circa 1980-2011; cuid8008; 544999
    This box contains materials from NYCOSH retreats and assorted news articles, speeches, and correspondence, likely collected by Joel Shufro.
  - Box 61, 1989-2003; cuid8009; 544997
    This box contains campaign files related to NYCOSH's advocacy on the issues of workers' compensation, needlestick injuries (as a member of the Needlestick Injury Prevention Coalition), and medical monitoring. Other campaign files pertain to opposition to various OSHA reform bills that proposed to weaken the agency's enforcement powers, the "reinvention" of OSHA in 1995, and the New York State Occupational Safety and Health Training and Education program.
    The box also includes subject files on Presidents Bush and Clinton's relationships to OSHA, specific members of congress, members of affiliated organizations, Workers Memorial Days, asbestos, the Cornell/NYCOSH Occupational Safety and Health Certificate Program, and other topics. There are a few files containing citations and complaints against the Public Employee Safety and Health program (PESH) of the New York State Department of Labor, New York State United Teachers' applications to the New York state Occupational Safety and Health Training grant, and a small amount of NYCOSH office administration material.
  - Ingoing and Outgoing Correspondence, 2003-2011; cuid8010; 545000 (Box 62)
  - Box 63, 1981-2011; cuid8011; 545064